The Sikong family's realm
司空氏の天下
Cannot be stained with the blood of our own clan again
同族の血をこれ以上流してはいけない
Father clearly said this wound was almost healed
父上ははっきりとこの傷はもうすぐ治ると言われた
How is this
これはどうやって
I've thought for a long time
父はしばらく考えた
And decided to pass the throne to your elder brother
やはりお前の兄に位を譲る準備をするつもりだ
In times of chaos
乱世の争い
Xuan Kingdom needs bravery
宣国が必要としているのは勇気です
Fierceness and ruthlessness
残忍で手段を選ばない人
But to govern in peace
しかし太平の世を治める
Your elder brother is more suitable than I
あなたのお兄さんは私より
Or you
あなたより
More suitable
どちらも適しています
Do you think I'm being unfair?
お父さんがえこひいきしていると思いますか
No
ない
Your son is willing to assist elder brother
私わたくしは兄上を助けることを望みます
I remember everything
父も覚えている
The Tiannan Pass battlefield
天南関の戦場
You alone lured Shilang into the pass
あなたは一人で石の狼を城内に入れた
That battle
あの戦い
You were hit by two blades
あなたは二カ所刺されている
Got back on your horse and fought again
まだ馬に乗って戦う
Further north
さらに北へ
Your chest
あなたの胸
Shoulder
肩
Back
背中
All have arrow wounds
みんな矢で傷ついている
Every wound you suffered for Xuan Kingdom
あなたが宣国のために受けた一つ一つの傷
I remember
父も覚えている
Father
父
Your temper is most like mine
あなたの気性は父に最も似ています
I sometimes think
お父さんは時々考え込むことがある
When the realm is at peace
天下が平和になるまで待つ
You can travel the mountains and rivers for me
お前は父の代わりに山河を旅してきなさい
See beautiful scenery and people everywhere
あちこちで美しい景色や美人を見て回る
Free as an immortal
自由に遊ぶ神仙
But after all, some things
でも結局いくつかのことは
I must burden you with
父はそれをあなたに背負わせざるを得ない
Father
父
Your elder brother has it hard
あなたのお兄さんは簡単な人ではありません
Help him for me
父親の代わりに彼を援助する
Assist him
彼を助ける
And protect what we two
私たち二人のこともよく守ってね
Worked so hard to conquer
苦労して切り開いたこの土地
Second son
次男
Can you promise me?
父さんに応えられるか
Your son promises
息子は父に約束した
Your son guarantees to do everything to protect Xuan Kingdom
私は必ず全力を尽くして宣国を守ることを約束します
Rise
起きて
Good child
いい子